IL Cafe we have you covered
welcome to aisle Cafe this is sheetal
and yes it is a subject that I have some
personal experience in having dealt with
international travel insurance now this
is really important because I hope you
are not one of those people who has ever
known anyone who has figured that oh my
God I should have not taken this
insurance only because that my dear
friends happens to a lot of people when
they go traveling with the best of
intention with the idea of having a
fabulous time with your friends and
family and then find themselves in a
dire situation uh with no insurance and
this is something then that's too late
to fix you plan every detail itinerary
is like every minute of every hour is
like sorted out but this one thing
people haven't done you don't want to
really mean it you don't want to be in
this position I've been there and done
that I'm super delighted therefore to be
talking about a subject that all of us
should be focusing on seeing as we are
like traveling a lot nowadays right
after the pandemic you just you know
decided boss have to do something have
to take off all those uh places and
destinations in our wishlist list so yes
the person who's going to be joining us
today is someone who's been with the
organization in fact I was a key player
in launching the travel insurance side
of things in icsu Lombard way back in
2003 so a long time uh his name is
pankaj srivastav and he is the head of
motor broking Affinity art travel agency
thank you so much pankaj and welcome to
Isle Cafe thank you sheetal and thanks
for having me absolutely as you said
correctly uh people take it sometimes
take it very lightly you need to
understand travel is like a safety net
for a person who's traveling abroad and
you can have a huge Peace of Mind once
you have a revolution with you it is not
only the medical issues which you deal
with when you are abroad out of India
it's exorbitant it's very very high for
a small thing which goes around let's
say around 10 000 or 20 000 that can
cost you Millions abroad so it's a
safety net and absolutely kind of peace
of mind and not only medical you have
hundreds of other benefits like uh your
package loss your package delay your
trip consideration your trip delay X the
number of features over there the
Absolutely I'll say it's advisement
whenever you're telling travel as you
talk about doing a ticketing in the
proper time a hotel it's absolutely my
take is actually mandatory uh it's not
by the government to take up this kind
of travel insurance with you yeah really
you know when you book tickets sometimes
you see that option over there and get
you gloss over it right and you don't
realize this till you come to that point
of an eventuality now the safety net
aspect of things right I want you to
dwell a little bit punger on that
subject because people uh say that you
know they only imagine the best out of
the best outcome of a planned holiday or
a planned trip somewhere and they don't
really think of it as a safety net they
think of it as an expense so please help
us understand and you know clarify that
it is not really an expense it is like a
peace of mind that you're investing in
I'll tell you is
I think it is kind of an investment I
mean maybe if you're somebody planning a
trip he has a good amount of money I'm
not saying but it won't be Beyond one
person or two percent of your entire
cost another thing anybody ranging from
zero years a newborn baby took 85 years
of a person he can take a travel
insurance plan without any kind of
medical examination here and once you
take this this thing you know if
anything happens whether it is a packet
delay as I said the package has not
arrived or it's anything loss of belong
belongings or if something goes Haywire
all kinds of features available in this
travel insurance uh in fact the biggest
would be the medical evacuation which I
can I am pretty sure you would be
traveling into this later on fantastic
so before we come to that point right
pankaj I want to understand a little bit
about icse Lombard's travel insurance
product you know could you tell us a
little bit about the benefits you
explained some of the typical benefits
of
specifically with respect to the ICICI
lumbar product would be great to
understand excellent question so there
are huge features available just to talk
about few let's say about uh about a
personal accident anything happens to
you or anything happens to a third party
you're liable to pay a huge amount of
fine over there that's taken care by the
Israel Embark policy another feature
would be like a dental insurance
wherever you are traveling you anything
might happen to you these all are the
cover third party claims and the most
important feature about the medical
execution and if you have reached a
place where there is no evacuation there
is no anything available to you to go
from one question another place and
there is features come in like a medical
invention but there are a lot of
benefits in the icslo policies now
unexpected events right one hears a lot
about these unexpected events that's a
phrase that we encounter a lot when it
comes to uh you know getting travel
insurance tell us a little bit about you
know what this really means when you use
or see a phrase like that a in a
insurance document so if you're
traveling there are people who travel to
let's say Europe Middle East uh
to you as people refer to when they are
going to Middle East they say it might
not be so expensive so generally people
don't tend to buy a policy people are
driving to Europe a fracture can cost
you around a million bucks in Indian
rupees it is so expensive and once you
have taken this policy they are covered
for each and everything over there it's
absolutely cashless you just need to go
to the hospital show the policy uh give
them the policy number and rest the
doctors will do they will not even
bother you or they will not even ask you
for anything you can just just go and
come clean out you know I hear you loud
and clear and I was I opened this for a
particular you know podcast with a
personal example saying that I've been
there and done that and you mentioned a
fracture my father had a fracture and
following the fracture he had a stroke
and it was unbelievable because I think
the bill was about upwards of 250 or 300
that is really what you can get uh you
know confronted with when you are in a
very innocuous holiday to spend time
with family and friends so you're
absolutely right about the fact that
some of these numbers we don't realize
it can have high impact I want to ask
you one more question about the duration
most people think only one week I'm
going only for 15 days you know what's
going to happen in that smaller time
frame uh there are senior citizens who
travel for a longer period of time to
certain kinds of countries where the
Visa availability is for a longer period
so you want to stay the maximum
especially if you're visiting your
family right
um so tell us a little bit about the
duration and what's ideal is it like I
don't need a travel insurance if I'm
only traveling for three four days
which starts from seven days uh 280 days
so if a person going in a U.S
specifically for her daughter's
pregnancy or something for that so you
have a policy till 180 days there are
also plants which are called as multi
drip where you can travel as many times
you want to with a maximum duration of
45 days and also student plans where
there are students who go out of India
to travel to study they are there for
earlier two years we have the policies
covered for one year two years and three
years no thank you for telling us about
those different options now here's um
the thing about budgets right everyone
travels these days I think travel has
just become one of these things that's
become more accessible for a variety of
reasons but still there is a budget all
of us have a budget and sometimes it's a
tight budget it what would your pointers
be when uh what would you say to someone
who's saying oh but I have a tight
budget for my travel this year what
would you tell them I think I don't know
people how much they are aware of and
whatever they are looking at but uh
going for a vanilla uh kind of a product
as I said it would not even cost you one
percent or two percent of your entire
traveling cost and it's somebody who is
looking for a huge amount of variety
where looking at a a cover of a million
dollar uh with all features I think it
would not even go more than two and a
half three percent I think it's
absolutely safe and you have a huge
piece of a file a person taking the the
entire entire Coupe in terms of the
product like if something happens if by
any chance by any misunderstanding
accident if we if he lets it is not able
to catch these flights
because of the daily translation of
course you have missed it the entire
thing is covered under this gamut so I'm
saying uh somebody paying one or two
percent of the entire traveling cost
which is not as much as we are talking
about and you have a total Peace of Mind
where you don't need to think about this
kind of circumstances which can happen
in a foreign absolutely peace of mind
and that too you don't want to be lumped
at the end of it all with financial
hardship that takes you years to recover
from right the impact of some of these
events unexpected events can be uh
they're not here and now they're not
momentary they can have a long-term
effect on all your plans for your life
if it's a big number that's involved and
if it's a medical kind of an emergency
of course the trip delays and those kind
of things are a different uh kettle of
fish altogether now any pointers for
someone who's planning an international
trip uh final pointers and is wondering
whether they need travel insurance how
would you just summarize the five or ten
minute conversation we've had so far
pankaj for all of these folks absolutely
so as I said there are many countries
today if you
these uh these consulates would not even
give you a Visa unless until you have a
travel issues with you because they they
don't want people coming over there
between their trips their burdened with
this kind of a expensive things I am
saying with a small amount of uh this
thing you can have a full Peace of Mind
any people who travel to foreign
[Music]
about your hotels as you plan about your
passes as you think about where you want
to go what you want to do because every
other month or maybe every other year
you won't be traveling uh to a foreign
land I think it is absolutely
appropriate or mandatory I think for a
piece of Mind person that you take such
kind of insurance
absolutely you know peace of mind is
important you brought up the Switzerland
uh you know examples I'm thinking over
here people want to be doing a yes
Chopra type of a scene over there you
know wearing chiffon saree doing
Rishi Kapoor colorful sweaters pancake
all these photo ops are there why don't
you just enjoy that instead of worrying
about my God you know what happens if I
don't have travel insurance important
point to have clarified you know I made
a mental note of all these things and I
was like oh my God if pankaj goes away
from here then I can't ask him this
question so it's been that kind of a
conversation but the mind is like
full-on questions are happening and
you're giving me all the answers and I'm
still thinking
so anyway I think we've done a great uh
you know sort of um capture of all the
essentials when it comes to travel
insurance especially in the
international context of things and all
thanks to you pankaj and one last
question out of syllabus totally what's
on your travel uh wish list maybe two
destinations that you have always wanted
to visit I love traveling uh personally
as well I have to travel a lot in terms
of official this thing Norway
ah did you manage to catch the Northern
Lights
oh okay we went to there it was raining
the entire day but we were able to
manage only for four to five minutes but
I think those four to five minutes might
have been just spectacular right this is
like on a lot of people's bucket list of
things to do like I will go to Norway or
the Scandinavian countries and watch the
northern lights and come back so lucky
you had a chance and uh lucky for us
that you were here to tell us all about
travel insurance today here's wishing
you many more happy travels and safe
travels going forward as well
nice talking to you and thanks for
having me here again uh have a great day
YouTube